<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>By the Lord Lieutenant and councell upon consideration of the annexed instrument, whereby it is concluded and accorded that there be a further continuation of the cessation of armes ... untill the last day of Iuly, 1645 ...</title>
            <author>Ireland. Lord Lieutenant (1641-1649 : Ormonde)</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1645</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 12 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 1 1-bit group-IV TIFF page image.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-04">2011-04 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A46082</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing I666</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R43290</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">27135018</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 27135018</idno>
            <idno type="VID">109994</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A46082)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 109994)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 1721:30)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>By the Lord Lieutenant and councell upon consideration of the annexed instrument, whereby it is concluded and accorded that there be a further continuation of the cessation of armes ... untill the last day of Iuly, 1645 ...</title>
                  <author>Ireland. Lord Lieutenant (1641-1649 : Ormonde)</author>
                  <author>Ormonde, James Butler, Duke of, 1610-1688.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([1] p.).   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>s.n.,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[S.l. :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1645]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Other title information from first lines of text.</note>
                  <note>"Given at His Majesties castle of Dublin, 24. Iuly, 1645."</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in Bodleian Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Ireland --  History --  1625-1649.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-11</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2008-01</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-07</date>
            <label>Lauren Proux</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-07</date>
            <label>Lauren Proux</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-09</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="letter">
            <pb facs="tcp:109994:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <head>¶ By the Lord Lieutenant and Councell.</head>
            <opener>
               <salute>ORMONDE.</salute>
            </opener>
            <p>
               <seg rend="decorInit">V</seg>Pon conſideration of the annexed Inſtrument, whereby it is concluded and accor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ded that there be a further continuation of the Ceſſation of Armes, &amp; of all Acts of hoſtility in this Kingdome, untill the laſt day of <hi>Iuly, 1645.</hi> at the houre of twelve of the clocke the ſame day. We the Lord Lieutenant and Councell doe by this Proclamation in His Majeſties Name, Ratifie, confirme and publiſh the ſame, And do require all His Majeſties Subjects whom it may concerne by Sea and by Land to take notice thereof, and yeeld all due obedience therunto in all the parts thereof.</p>
            <closer>
               <dateline>
                  <hi>Given at his Majeſties Caſtle of</hi> Dublin, <date>24. Iuly, 1645.</date>
               </dateline>
               <signed>Geo. Cloyne. Cha. Lambart. Arthur Chicheſter. Fr. Willoughby. Tho. Lucas. Robert Forth. G. Wentworth.</signed>
               <lb/>GOD SAVE THE KING.</closer>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <p>
               <hi>
                  <seg rend="decorInit">W</seg>HEREAS</hi> Articles of Ceſſation of Armes were agreed and concluded on at <hi>Sigginſtowne</hi> in the County of <hi>Kil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dare,</hi> the fifteenth day of <hi>September,</hi> in the nineteenth year of His Maieſties Raigne, By and between Us the Lord Lieutenant by the name of <hi>IAMES</hi> Marques of <hi>Ormonde,</hi> Lieutenant Generall of His Maieſties Armie in the Kingdome of <hi>Ireland,</hi> For and in the Name of our Gracious Soveraigne Lord <hi>CHARLES</hi> by the grace of God, King of Great Brittaine, <hi>France,</hi> and <hi>Ireland, &amp;c.</hi> By vertue of His Maieſties Commiſſion bearing date at <hi>Dublin,</hi> the laſt day of <hi>Auguſt,</hi> in the ſaid nineteenth year of His Maieſties Raign, of the one parte, And <hi>Donogh</hi> Lord Viſcount <hi>Muskery,</hi> and others authorized by His Maieſties Roman Catholicke Subiects then in Armes in the ſaid Kingdome, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> of the other parte: Which Ceſſation of Armes was by the ſaid Articles to continue for one whole year, beginning the <hi>15.</hi> of <hi>September, 1643.</hi> at the houre of twelve of the clock of the ſaid day. And whereas by His Maieſties Commiſſion under the Great Seale of <hi>England,</hi> dated the foure and twentieth day of <hi>Iune 1644.</hi> We the Lord Lieutenant are authorized to Treat concerning the ſetling &amp; eſtabliſhing of a firme and perfect Peace within this Kingdom. And wheras We the Lord Lieutenant by vertue of His Maieſties Authority entruſted with Vs as His Lieutenant Generall, and Generall Governor of this His Kingdom, and by advice of the Councell, and For and in the Name of His Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ieſty on the one part, And he ſaid Lord Viſc. <hi>Muskery,</hi> and others deputed and Authorized in that behalfe by His Maieſties ſaid Subiects now or late in Armes in this Kingdome, of the other parte, did on the fifth day of <hi>September</hi> laſt conclude, and accord that there ſhould be a further Ceſſation of Armes, &amp; of all Acts of Hoſtility in this Kingdom, untill the firſt day of <hi>December</hi> then next, at the houre of twelve of the clock of the ſaid day. And whereas We the Lord Lieutenant by vertue of His Maieſties Authority entruſted with Vs as His Lieutenant Generall and Generall Governor of this his Kingdom, and by advice of the Councell, and For, and in the Name of His Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ieſty on the one part, And the ſaid Lord Viſcount <hi>Muskery.</hi> and others Deputed and authorized in that behalfe by His Maieſties ſaid Subiects now, or late in Armes in this Kingdome of the other parte, did on the 11 day of <hi>November</hi> laſt, conclude and accord that there ſhould be a further continuation of the ſaid Ceſſation of Armes and of all Acts of Hoſtility in this Kingdom, untill the laſt day of <hi>Ianuary,</hi> then next, at the houre of twelve of the clock of the ſame day. And whereas We the Lord Lieutenant by vertue of His Maieſties authori<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty entruſted with Vs, as His Lievtenant Generall and Generall Governour of this his Kingdome and by advice of the Counſell and for and in the Name of his Maieſtie of the one part, and the ſaid Lord Viſcount <hi>Muskery</hi> and others deputed and authorized in that behalfe by his Maieſties ſaid Subiects now or late in Armes in this Kingdom, of the other part, did on the laſt day of <hi>December</hi> laſt conclude and accord that there ſhould be a further continuation of the ſaid Ceſſation of Armes and of all Acts of Hoſtility in this Kingdome untill the laſt day of <hi>March</hi> then next at the houre of twelve of the clock of the ſaid day. And whereas We the Lord Lievtenant by vertue of His Maieſties authority entruſted with Vs as his Lievtenant Generall and Generall Governour of this His Kingdome and by ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vice of the Councell and for and in the Name of his Maieſty on the one part, And the ſaid Lord viſcount <hi>Muskery</hi> and others deputed and authorized in that behalfe by His Maieſties ſaid Subiects now or late in Armes in this Kingdome on the other part, did on the firſt day of <hi>March</hi> laſt, conclude and accord that there ſhould be a further continuation of the ſaid Ceſſation of Armes and of all acts of Hoſti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lity in this Kingdome untill the laſt day of <hi>April</hi> then next, at the houre of twelve of the clock of the ſame day. And whereas We the Lord Lieutenant, by vertue of His Maieſties Authority entruſted with Vs, as His Lieutenant Generall and Generall Governour of this His Kingdome, and by advice of the Councell, and For and in the Name of His Maieſty of the one part, and the ſaid Lo. Viſcount <hi>Mus<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>kery,</hi> and others deputed and authorized in that behalfe, by His Maieſties ſaid Subiects now or late in Armes in this Kingdome of the other part, did on the one and twentieth day of <hi>April</hi> laſt conclude and accord, that there ſhould be a further continuation of the ſaid Ceſſation of Armes and of all Acts of hoſtility in this Kingdome, untill the twentieth day of <hi>May</hi> then next, at the houre of twelve of the clock the ſame day. And whereas We the Lord Lieutenant by vertue of his Maieſties Authority entruſted with Vs as his Lieute<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nant Generall and Generall Governour of this his Kingdom and by advice of the Councell, and for and in the name of his Maieſty of the one part, and the ſaid Lord Viſc. <hi>Muskery,</hi> and others deputed &amp; authorized in that behalfe, by his Maieſties ſaid Subiects now or late in Armes in this Kingdom of the other part, did on the ſixteenth day of <hi>May laſt 1645.</hi> conclude &amp; accord that there ſhould be a further continuation of the ſaid Ceſſation of Armes &amp; of all Acts of hoſtility in this Kingdom untill the fourth day of <hi>Iune</hi> then next, at the hour of <hi>12.</hi> of the clock the ſame day. And whereas We the Lord Lieutenant by vertue of His Maieſties Authority entruſted with Vs as his Lieutenant Generall and Generall Governour of this his Kingdome, and by advice of the Councell, and for and in the Name of his Maieſty of the one part, And the ſaid Lord viſc. <hi>Muskery,</hi> and others deputed and authorized in that behalfe, by his Maieſties ſaid Subiects now or late in armes in this Kingdome of the other parte, did on the firſt day of <hi>Iune 1645.</hi> conclude and accord that there ſhould be a further continuation of the ſaid Ceſſation of Armes and of all Acts of Hoſtility in this Kingdome untill the eighteenth day of <hi>Iune</hi> one thouſand ſix hundred forty and five, at the houre of twelve of the clocke the ſame day. And whereas We the Lord Lievtenant by vertue of his Maieſties authority entruſted with Vs as his Lievtenant Generall and Gene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rall Governor of this his Kingdome and by advice of the Councell, and for and in the name of His Maieſty of the one part and the ſaid Lord Viſcount <hi>Muskery</hi> and others deputed and authorized in that behalfe by his Maieſties ſaid ſubiects now or late in armes in this Kingdom of the other part, did on the fourteenth day of <hi>Iune 1645.</hi> conclude and accord that there ſhould be a further continuation of the ſaid Ceſſation of Armes and of all acts of hoſtility in this Kingdome, untill the fourth day of <hi>Iuly 1645.</hi> at the houre of <hi>12</hi> of the clock the ſame day. And whereas We the Lord Lieutenant by vertue of His Maieſties Authority entruſted with Vs as his Lieutenant Generall and Generall Governour of this his Kingdome, and by advice of the Councell, And For and in the Name of his Maieſtie of the one parte, And <hi>Patrick Darcy,</hi> and <hi>Geffrey Browne,</hi> Eſquires. deputed and authorized by his Maieſties ſaid Subiects now or late in Armes in this Kingdome of the other parte, did on the thirtieth day of <hi>Iune, 1645.</hi> conclude and accord that there ſhould be a further con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tinuation of the ſaid Ceſſation of Armes, &amp; of all Acts of hoſtility in this Kingdome, untill the <hi>18th</hi> day of <hi>Iuly, 1645.</hi> at the houre of <hi>12</hi> of the clock the ſame day. And in regard We deſire to prevent any inconvenience that may happen by a too late continuing of the preſent Ceſſation for ſuch a longer time as may in likelyhood give the freer and better opportunity towards facilitating the expected peace. We the Lord Lieutenant by vertue of his Maieſties authority entruſted with Vs as his Lieutenant Generall and Generall Governour of this his Kingdome, and by advice of the Councell, and For and in the Name of his Maieſtie of the one parte, and we the ſaid Lord viſc. <hi>Muskery, Nicholas Plunket</hi> Eſq. Sir <hi>Rob. Talbot</hi> Barronet. <hi>Dermot ô Bryen, Patrick Darcy,</hi> &amp; <hi>Geffrey Brown,</hi> Eſquires. Deputed and Au<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thorized in that behalfe by his Maieſties ſaid ſubiects now or late in Armes in this Kingdome &amp;c. of the other parte, have concluded and accorded, and it is accordingly hereby concluded and accorded that there be a further continuation of ſaid Ceſſation of Armes and of all Acts of Hoſtility in this Kingdome, untill the laſt day of <hi>Iuly, 1645.</hi> at the hour of twelve of the clock the ſame day, upon the like Ar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ticles &amp; agreements, to all intents &amp; purpoſes as are expreſſed in the ſaid former Articles of Ceſſation, concluded on at <hi>Sigginſtown,</hi> on the <hi>15</hi> of <hi>September, 1643.</hi> And as if the ſaid Ceſſation firſt agreed on had continuance untill the laſt day of <hi>Iuly, 1645.</hi> at the houre of twelve of the clock the ſame day. In witneſſe whereof, the ſaid Lord Lieutenant to that part of this agreement which remaines with the Lord viſc. <hi>Muskery, Nicholas Plunket,</hi> Sir <hi>Robert Talbot, Dermot ô Bryen, Patrick Darcy,</hi> and <hi>Geffrey Browne,</hi> hath put his hand and ſeale, and the ſaid Lord viſc. <hi>Muskery, Nicholas Plunket,</hi> Sir <hi>Robert Talbot, Dermot ô Bryen, Patrick Darcy,</hi> and <hi>Geffrey Browne,</hi> to that part of this agreement which remaines with the ſaid Lord Lieutenant, have put their hands and ſeales the fifteenth day of <hi>Iuly, 1645.</hi> and in the one and twentieth peace of His Maieſties Raigne.</p>
            <closer>
               <signed>Muskery. N. Plunket. Rob. Talbot. Dermot ô Bryen. Geffr. Browne.</signed>
            </closer>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
